has more than 210 million customers globally,
what is driving this growth?
What type of users are commonly using the platform?
- Yeah, yeah, thank you for noticing that.
A lot of the growth were driven by, of course,
the exciting things happening in the crypto markets.
There are more users that we see growing
on the silent majority that people
from across the world globally,
everyday people using crypto for everyday purposes.
Specifically, a lot of them are using stablecoin
to send across the borders.
We see a lot of the flows from developed countries
to developing countries to Latin America, to India, et cetera,
because blockchain offers a much cheaper way
of sending money across.
- It's very interesting and there's a big use case
on the remittances aside.
So that's a very interesting use case.
You also see other activity, like how other,
like the average size or the customer balances,
for example, for lack of a better word, on Trust Wallet.
- It's actually very bipolar.
We got people who might be just having like $10
or $20 here and there.
We also have a digit, nine digit million dollars
of the balances that the users will be storing
on the blockchain through self custody.
- And what is the biggest challenge when it comes,
let's say, to user acquisition?
Is it education for them to be able
to get comfortable with self custody?
Is it just knowledge of the tool?
Like what, or is just market beta of crypto adoption,
like you mentioned, that silo majority
that are just embarking onto crypto?
- Yeah.
I think there are definitely things that can do better
with how the product, the educations make it easier
and safer for people.
But at the same time, the more important is
how useful crypto can be in people's daily life.
- Interesting.
You know, for a long time, when it came to self custody,
a user experience was a problem.
There was this UX problem with self custody wallets.
You know, my mom can maybe go use a centralized crypto exchange,
but maybe for her to use a self custody wallet,
it's more complicated.
What do you think is being addressed to solve that issue?
At least improve it.
And you believe it's still an issue today?
- I think the hardest issue that still exists
and will continue to exist is how to trade off
between simple, easy to use and give people full control
and freedom of their assets,
which is the essence of self custody.
And we're now having more technologies such as
sharding the keys or a lot of people to back up
their secret phrase encrypted format in cloud storage.
But they will always at some point,
sacrifice this a bit on users 100%,
the only one control their own assets.
I think ultimately, it will come down to
different people might have different needs
and they will choose across the scale
what works best for them.
So now we see more products coming up,
more options coming up,
so you can fee for people's different purposes.
- When you're talking about the different needs from users,
where does physical security come and play?
We've seen recently all these kidnappings
and issues that happen in the crypto community.
Isn't the increased risk with self custody
that these events can go wrong?
Whereas if your assets are a third party custodian,
there's not much you can actually do to move those assets.
- I actually don't think the core problem
is if the criminal decides to commit crime on kidnap,
it's based on whether this person's self custody or not.
Because ultimately, they will be asking for the money
and regarding to how you move the money is your issue.
I think it's more about there are increasing targets
that crypto industry give exposure to.
I have known and have seen people working together
in the industry across the law enforcement globally
to help to make sure that builders in our space
are feeling safe to continue to innovate.
- And do you believe there'll be a day
where the self custody industry will meet to fall
or have more regulatory oversight
just by the nature of how things are going
or the sacrosanct belief of not your keys,
not your coins will continue to remain true,
at least definitely in the crypto ecosystem?
- Yeah, I think it depends on jurisdictions
will take a stance on what is fundamental rights
for citizens.
I think the US take a stance that self custody
is a fundamental rights
and you will not be having regulation
around if it's true self custody.
There might be different degrees of oversight
if it comes down to semi custody
or some sort of custodian responsibilities going in there.
That might be an interesting time
to see what might be the opportunities over there.
- And outside of just let's say holding private keys
of various digital assets,
are you seeing users use it for different purposes?
Are you seeing more users use real world assets,
tokenized products?
Are you seeing them for staking?
How are you seeing the user base adapt
how they're using the crypto?
- Oh absolutely, besides remittance,
there are two major routes that people go to.
The first one is, of course,
people find crypto world to be a lot more interesting.
Now they get their food into the door,
they're learning about different kind of crypto concepts
and then getting their food on.
Of course, one of the primary behavior might be swaps
or debt engagement, those kind of issues.
Another area is, even with stablecoin,
there are a lot more traditional finance,
RWA and DeFi strategies that can help people
to are yield in a safe way.
And those are some opportunities that we see are increasing
that help people to better preserve their money
and combat interest rate inflation better than their banks.
Actually, you mentioned banks.
In a way, the beauty of self-costity wallets,
you have your assets there, you can generate yield,
you don't need to put it into a bank.
Do you see the banks as potential competitors?
Or the banks who see you as a potential competitor
down the line as people can take their assets out,
keep them there, get better yield, frankly,
than they're getting into the bank
and they're master of their own keys?
- I think it's not going to be wanted,
that's the competitor.
It's ultimately the blockchain,
which the user's funds are in, right?
Because different from banks,
we cannot move users' money.
What we can do is how to best inform
and provide opportunities surface to the user
so they make their own decisions.
And I think that's a fundamental difference
between banks will do services for you
while we, as a software product,
is to help people to do better decisions for themselves.
- I think it's very interesting you mentioned
how in the US now it's seen as a fundamental right,
the right of self-costity.
And I think this is going to be very, very interesting
development to watch over the coming years.
- No, last question, when it's really,
let's say we have this interview in 2035, 10 years from now,
how do you see the future of self-costity evolve?
Like where do you think it will be in 10 years from now?
- Yeah, I think the key question behind self-costity
is what rights and power do people have
with their most valuable assets?
I think right now we're just looking at self-costity
with crypto, how about with other assets?
And then what does other assets mean?
How about data?
If the future of the world is going to be on-chain
or even AI driven world, data is going to be very valuable.
How do people preserve their own data ownership?
How do people preserve their identity ownership?
So if we're talking about self-costity becomes like,
how do people preserve and protect
their most valuable assets and the toolkit
and the power that they have around it?